DEAN WILCOX

LACEY, WASHINGTON | C: (832)-573-7963 | WILCOX.DEAN93@GMAIL.COM

LinkedIn & GitHub links:

Professional Objective:

Highly motivated transitioning service member with an active Secret security clearance. Currently enrolled in the Washington Vets to Tech (WaV2T) program, specializing in Cloud Application Development, with an expected completion date of December 2023. This program grants 18 college credits towards a bachelor's degree in computer science. My studies include programming languages such as: Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML5, SQL, as well as the Linux operating system.

Actively seeking career opportunities in the domains of Cloud/Application Development or Software Development. Will bring a solution-focused mindset, exceptional leadership acumen, and a collaborative approach to teamwork. These skills were developed during my time in the United States Army and during my over four years as a Parts Manager and Sales and Marketing Advisor. I am eager to find a company that fosters continuous growth where I can proudly contribute and learn over the long term while ensuring customers' needs are met and exceeded while delivering the best possible customer service.

Education

Central Texas College

Lacey, Washington Expected grad date 2024

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

St. Martin's University – August 2023 – present Certificate in Computer Science Expected graduation December 15, 2023 Classes:

- CSC160 Intro to Computer Software
- CSC230 Intro to Web Development
- CSC235 Intro to Linux and Linux Admin
- CSC205 Application Programming Lang & Tools
- CSC340 Data Structures and Algorithms
- CSC457 Developing Cloud Solutions

Programing Languages and OS

Familiar - Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Linux

Skills

Leadership
Communication
Team-focused

Problem solver
Detail oriented
Customer service

• Trainer • Result oriented • Creative

Work History

Wheeled Vehicle Mechanic,

09/2020 - Current

United States Army – JBLM, Washington

- Responsible for supervising and performing maintenance and recovery operations on wheeled vehicles and associated items.
- Used applicable references for inspecting, testing, and/or replacing parts.
- Managed a service schedule for 90+ vehicles and ensured services and repairs did not run past due.
- Managed 10-15 people and ensured they had a full workload daily.
- Taught military-related classes to ensure soldiers knew their job and performed their duties in a safe manner.

Parts Manager, 11/2017 – 06/2020

Team Mancuso Powersports Southwest – Houston, Texas

- Managed inventory levels and turn rates on a \$1,200,000 inventory.
- Maintained smooth relations with 20+ suppliers which allowed for mutually beneficial business growth.
- Managed purchase orders, backorders, and posted all inventory adjustment reports in a timely manner.
- Managed 4-8 employees to ensure the department ran smoothly.
- Monthly and yearly evaluations for all employees in the department.
- Grew from \$417k in sales in 2017 to \$486k in 2018 while maintaining 40% profit margins.
- Raised profit margins by 6% over a two-year period by obtaining better deals through suppliers and implementing new sales tactics in-store.

Sales and Marketing Advisor, 10/2016 – 11/2017

Western Powersports – Boise, Idaho (Remote position in Houston, Texas)

- Outside sales representative to 43 Powersports dealers across North Houston.
- Differentiated the quality of products and services through presentations and demonstrations.
- Provided value added services such as inventory management and problem solving.
- Qualified buyers by understanding needs and interests.
- Communicated with dealers via email, phone, and in person to help resolve issues/complaints.
- Grew business by 12-15% competing with years prior.